Preliminary Inventory of the Iran Freedom Foundation Records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject file
  - Directory of ambassadors and other officials, by country, undated (Box 38)
  - Farhang, Mansour and pro-Khomeini activities in the United States, undated (Box 38)
  - Iran-Iraq War--Child soldiers, 1984 (Box 38)
  - Islamic groups in the U.S. newsletters, 1992-1993 (Box 38)
  - Pahlavi, Farah. Statement on first anniversary of death of Mohammad Reza Shah, 1981 (Box 38)
  - Miscellaneous, 1989 (Box 38)
- Publicity file
  - Drafts of writings, undated (Box 38)
  - General, 1979-1980 (Box 38)
  - Plans for nationalist counter-revolution in Iran, 1981 (Box 38)
  - Notes, undated (Box 38)
- Subject file
  - Anti-Khomeini demonstration flyer, 1980 June (Box 39)
  - Assassination of A. A. Tabatabai, 1980 (Box 39)
  - Bakhtiar, Chapour. Speeches, writings, and related materials, 1978-1981 (Box 39)
- Clippings on Iran, 1992 (Box 39)
- Publicity file. Letters to IFF from President-elect Bill Clinton and Vice President-elect Al Gore, 1993 (Box 39)
- Correspondence and list of contacts, 1992-1993 (Box 39)
- Notes, undated (Box 39)
- Press reports on the Shah leaving Iran, 1978-1979 (Box 39)
- Miscellaneous. Human rights in Iran, hostages, clippings, 1980 (Box 39)
- Newspapers and clippings, 1980-1982 (Box 40)
- Radio program materials, drafts and notes, undated (Box 40)
- Publicity file
  - Draft of mission statement and purpose of IFF, undated (Box 40)
  - Activity report research materials, 1979-1980 (Box 40)
    Includes clippings and other documents supporting the activities of the IFF
- Subject file. Assassination of A. A. Tabatabai, 1980 (Box 40)
- Photographs of anti-Khomeini demonstration, 1982 (Box 40)
- Clippings related to Bakhtiar assassination plot, Iran's clerical leaders, and U.S.-Iranian relations, 1980 June-July (Box 41)
- Sketch of A. A. Tabatabai, 1980 (Box 41)
- "Law and Human Rights in the Islamic Republic of Iran; a Report Covering Events Within the Seven Month Period Following the Revolution of February 1979," Amnesty International, 1980 (Box 41)
- Publicity file (Box 41)
  - Letters, speeches, and other materials, 1979-1984 (Box 41)
    Includes legal records and activity reports
  - Transcripts of television and radio appearances, 1979-1980 (Box 41)
- A. A. Tabatabai personal correspondence, 1979 (Box 41)
- Press attaché of the Iranian embassy, Washington, D.C. correspondence, memoranda, and other materials, 1966-1979 (Box 42)
- Publicity file. Newsletters, speeches, and other materials, 1981-1983 (Box 42)
- Radio program materials, 1982-1983 (Box 42)
  Includes headlines, clippings, scripts, and notes
- Radio program materials, 1982-1983 (Box 43)
- Radio program materials, 1982 (Box 44)
- Newspapers and clippings on arms, oil, and illiteracy in Iran, 1975 (Box 44)
- Subject file (Box 44)
  - Islamic revolution--Early years, 1980 (Box 44)
  - Iran, 2500 year celebration, 1971 (Box 44)
    Includes information about Iran published under the Shah. In French and English
- Publicity file. Transcripts of radio and television appearances, clippings, and cables, 1979-1980 (Box 45)
- Iranian politics and history materials, 1964; 1971,; undated (Box 45)
- Subject file
  - Human rights in Iran, 1984 (Box 46)
  - Sadat, Anwar, 1980-1981 (Box 46)
- Publicity file
  - Mailing lists and contacts, undated (Box 46)
  - Research materials for interviews, 1979-1989 (Box 46)
    Includes newspapers, newswires, and notes
- "Report of the Staff's Study of Alleged Misconduct by Members of the House of Representatives Involving the Former Government of Iran," photocopy, 1979 October 24 (Box 47)
- Printed matter. Time, Newsweek, and other popular magazines featuring articles on the Shah, Iranian politics, and American involvement in the region, 1968-1987 (Box 47)
- Bakhtiar, Chapour communiqué, photocopy, 1981 January (Box 47)
- Printed matter from Iranian nationalist groups, 1983 (Box 48)
- Correspondence. Letters received, general, 1984-1985 (Box 48)
- Subject file
  - Aghilipour, H., Colonel, 1984-1986 (Box 48)
  - Assassination of A. A. Tabatabai, 1980 (Box 48)
  - Rushdie, Salman. Satanic Verses, 1989 (Box 48)
  - Terrorism, 1985 (Box 48)
  - Pahlavi, Mohammed Reza, Shah of Iran, 1976-1979 (Box 48)
- News wires and news clippings, 1979 February-March (Box 48)
- Press attaché of the Iranian embassy, Washington, D.C. file, 1960s-1970s (Box 48)
- Notes, drafts of writings, and miscellaneous (Box 48)
- Printed matter
  - Iran: In Defense of Human Rights. National Movement of the Iranian Resistance monograph, 1983 (Box 49)
  - Clippings and printed matter on the Islamic revolution, 1979-1987 (Box 49)
- Publicity file
  - Press contacts, undated (Box 49)
  - A. A. Tabatabai business cards, 1966-1979 (Box 49)
  - Lists of Iranian organizations and publications, undated (Box 49)
  - Drafts of speeches by M. R. Tabatabai, typescripts, 1981-1986 (Box 49)
- Darui, Farzad, 1984 (Box 49)
- Stamps, undated (Box 49)
- Zahedi, Ardeshir curriculum vita and Iranian embassy correspondence and memoranda, 1966-1978 (Box 49)
  Includes correspondence, clippings, and Congressional Record documents relating to Senator Larry MacDonald's support of Iran and denunciation of the Iranian Student Association in the United States
- Research materials and notes for interviews, undated (Box 50)
  Includes clippings and IFF newsletters
- Subject file
  - Death of Khomeini, 1989 (Box 50)
  - Anti-Khomeini demonstration planning materials, 1981-1983 (Box 50)
  - Zahedi, Ardeshir, 1977 (Box 50)
- Correspondence. Letters received, general, 1983-1986 (Box 50)
- Lyndon LaRouche comments on Khomeini regime, 1982 (Box 50)
- Publicity file. Newsletters, correspondence, and related materials, 1982-1986 (Box 51)
- Publicity file. Newsletters, correspondence, and related materials, 1982-1986 (Box 51)
- Printed matter. Iranian groups in exile newsletters and publications, 1980-1983 (Box 51)
- Press attaché of the Iranian embassy, Washington, D.C. correspondence and memoranda, 1977-1982 (Box 51)
- Photographs. Senator Jesse Helms, undated (Box 51)
- Research materials on Iran, 1980 (Box 51)
- Notes, undated (Box 51)
- A. A. Tabatabai personal file, 1974-1979 (Box 51)
- Miscellany, receipts, map, magazine (Box 51)
- Subject file
  - Iranian exile groups, 1981 (Box 52)
  - Return of hostages, 1981 (Box 52)
  - Braun, Jonathan (The Jewish Weekly) correspondence and articles, 1978 (Box 52)
    Includes correspondence with Ardeshir Zahedi and A. A. Tabatabai
- Clippings, 1980 (Box 52)
- Printed matter by or related to Lyndon LaRouche, including issues of Executive Intelligence Review and Investigative Leads, 1980-1984 (Box 53)
- "Census of Claims Against Iran" and "Census of Blocked Iranian Assets," Office of Foreign Assets Control, United States Department of the Treasury, undated (Box 53)
- Publicity file
  - Clippings, transcripts, and other materials, 1978-1980 (Box 54)
    Includes transcripts of radio and television appearances relating to the revolution, Carter's policies, and the aftermath
  - Transcript of program aired 1/9/81 Laura Hall Show KAYO M. R. Tabatabai," audiocassette tape and related correspondence (Box 54)
- Printed matter
  - "Islamic Terror in U.S.?," The Washington Times, 1985 June 20 (Box 55)
  - Iranian and American newspapers and magazines, 1980-1983 (Box 55)
    Includes Reader's Digest, Ashghar Agha, Harakat, Ghiam-i Iran
- Clippings and other research materials on Khomeini, 1984-1985 (Box 55)
- Iranian newspapers, 1980-1984 (Box 56)
- Iranian newspapers, 1980-1986 (Box 57)
- Video recordings, 1979-1981; undated
  Contains recordings of interviews on U-matic videocassettes, arranged chronologically by subject or title
  - "Iran Freedom Foundation Interview...Parts 1-4. Ali Tabatabai with Brad Edwards,", undated (Box 58)
  - "Iran Freedom Foundation: Panorama, WTTG TV (5), Washington, D.C.: A Discussion of Iran. Host: Ken Alvord. Guests: Ali Tabatabai, et al.,", 1979 November 12 (Box 58)
  - "Iran Freedom Foundation: CBS News Special Report: 'The Crisis in Iran--The Oil Cut-Off,' An Interview With Ali Tabatabai, WDVM TV/CBS Network,", 1979 November 12 (Box 58)
  - Ali A. Tabatabai interview, 1979 November 12 (Box 59)
  - "Interview with Mr. Ali A. Tabatabai, News Center Four, WNBC TV,", 1980 April 23 (Box 59)
    2 copies
  - "Interview with Ali A. Tabatabai of Iran, News Center Four, WNBC TV,", 1980 April 25 (Box 60)
  - "Cable Network News Interview, Freeman Show, Mr. Tabatabai,", 1981 August 31 (Box 60)
- Sound recordings, 1979-circa 1987; undated
  Compact sound cassettes and open reel tapes arranged by form then by subject chronologically
  - Compact sound cassettes, 1979-circa 1987
    - Interviews featuring Ali Akbar Tabatabai or Mohammad Reza Tabatabai, 1979-1984; undated (Box 61)
      - "A. A. Tabatabai, [Laura] Hall interview,", undated (Box 61)
      - "Ali A. Tabatabai interview with Dave Williams,", undated (Box 61)
      - "Ali A. Tabatabai interview with Pat Buchanan and Dr. Bakhtiar on WRC Radio,", undated (Box 61)
      - "Interview, WAZA FM Radio," 1979 November 15 "Interview with R. Day, WRC Radio NBC, 12:25-12:35,", 1979 November 16 (Box 61)
      - "Tabatabai interview with John Cooley (radio)-ABC,", 1979 October 10 (Box 61)
      - Side 1: "Interview with Barbara Lamont (CBS-Radio-NY) regarding changing of foreign minister," 1979 November 28 and "Interview with Jim Bohannon (WRC-NBC)," 1979 November 29; "Jim Bohannon interview, WRC Radio,", 1979 December 3? (Box 61)
      - "Ali A. Tabatabai Jackson Bain interview" (Box 61)
      - "Interview Ali A. Tabatabai duplicate" (Box 61)
      - "Ali A. Tabatabai interview hostage crisis,", circa 1980 (Folder 61)
      - LKS?, 1980 January 5 (Box 61)
        5 cassettes
      - "Ali Tabatabai on Laura Hall Show," 25 minutes, 1980 March 31 (Box 61)
      - "WRC, 4/9/80, 6-7 PM,", 1980 April 9 (Box 61)
      - "WRC Radio, Joel A. Spivak,", 1980 April 10 (Box 61)
      - "Spivak with Ali Tabatabai,", 1980 July 16 (Box 61)
      - "Mohammad Tabatabai,", 1980 September 24 (Box 61)
      - "Kevin Joyce-Tabatabai interview, WXYZ Detroit Radio,", 1980 September 27 (Box 61)
      - 1981 July 22 (Box 61)
      - "Pierre Salinger interview, Nightline,", 1981 July 29? (Box 61)
      - "Radio WPFW Washington, D.C., Mohammad Reza Tabatabai"; "Seda-i Azadi Iran, Mohammad Reza Tabatabai" (Box 61)
      - "Commentary, M. R. Tabatabai WLMD Radio Persian Program Washington, D.C.,", 1982 January 17 (Box 61)
      - "M. Tabatabai-Dr. Amini,", 1983 September 22 (Box 61)
      - "Mohammad Reza Tabatabai-Radio Azadi Iran,", 1984 (Box 61)
    - Dr. Chapour Bakhtiar interviews and related recordings, 1979-1982; undated
      - Unlabeled, undated (Box 61)
        4 cassettes
      - "Chapour Bakhtiar,", undated (Box 61)
      - "Payam-i Doktor Bakhtiar...," undated (Box 61)
      - "Bakhtiar message on Norouz (New Years),", undated (Box 61)
      - "Dr. Bakhtiar,", undated (Box 61)
      - "Navar Shumareh-yi Divvum-i Doktor Bakhtiar (Tape #2 of Dr. Bakhtiar),", undated (Box 61)
      - "Matn-i Payam-i Doktor Shapour Bakhtiar...,", undated (Box 61)
      - "Navar Shumareh-yi 6 Agha-yi Shapour Doktor Bakhtiar,", undated (Box 61)
      - "Neal Boortz Show WRNG, Atlanta, Georgia with Dr. Chapour Bakhtiar,", undated (Box 61)
      - "Dr. Ganji, Gen. Shojaei, Bakhtiar, etc.", undated (Box 61)
      - "Dr. Chapour Bakhtiar,", 1979 October (Box 61)
        3 cassettes
      - John K. Cooley telephone interview with Chapour Bakhtiar,", 1979 (Box 62)
      - "KAYO Bakhtiar Interview,", 1980 April 11 (Box 62)
      - "Dr. Bakhtiar Telephone Conversation,", 1982 May 27 (Box 62)
    - Alahazrat Reza Shah II recordings, circa 1982-circa 1987 (Box 62)
      See Boxes 31 and 32 for transcripts of some recordings. 27 cassettes
    - Death threats received by A. A. and M. R. Tabatabai, circa 1980-1984; undated (Box 62)
      7 cassettes
    - Death threat received by A. A. and M. R. Tabatabai, 1984 (Box 63)
    - Voice of Freedom and Voice of America radio program recordings, 1984; undated (Box 63)
      9 cassettes
    - Other recordings, 1979-1986; undated
      - "Mansur Rafizadeh on The Larry King Show,", undated (Box 63)
      - "Navār-i 4 Payām-i Noruzī,", undated (Box 63)
      - General Amiri, undated (Box 63)
      - "Bruce Henderson,", undated (Box 63)
      - "Guruh-i Vahdat-i Millī-i Iran, GRMI,", undated (Box 63)
      - Unlabeled, undated (Box 63)
      - "Neghab (Mask), Paris-Washington tel.,", undated (Box 63)
      - Amir'Abbas Huvayda on The Larry King Show, WTOP Radio, 5/6,", undated (Box 63)
        2 cassettes
      - "1979,", undated (Box 63)
      - "McNeal and Leherer Report,", 1981 January 21 (Box 63)
      - Barbara Walters interviews Saddam Hussein, 1981 July 1 (Box 63)
      - Nightline, Marvin Zonis, ABC, 1981 August 12 (Box 63)
      - Bahram Aryana, 1981 November 25 (Box 63)
      - "Letter to the Editor, Washington Post,", 1981 December 28 (Box 63)
      - Untitled, 1982 March 7-9 (Box 63)
      - "Bahram Aryana to Turkey,", 1982 March 18 (Box 63)
      - "Bahram Aryana to Turkey,", 1982 March 19 (Box 63)
      - Untitled, 1982 June 2 (Box 63)
      - "General Aryana-Ankara, Turkey,", 1982 June 23 (Box 63)
      - "M. R. Tabatabai I.F.F., General Aryana-Ankara,", 1982 (Box 63)
      - 1982 July 6-14 (Box 63)
      - Ghotbzadeh execution, Nightline, 1982 September 16 (Box 63)
      - "Telephone call to Dr. Ali Amini (Paris from Washington)," 1982 January 18; "Assad Homayoun-Kazemian, Darui's file," (Box 63)
      - Barbara Walters interview, 1985 January (Box 63)
      - 1985 (Box 63)
      - Nightline, on arms sales to Iran, 1986 December 18 (Box 63)
      - "Terrorism and the Washington Target-WMAL,", 1986 August 26 (Box 63)
      - Payām-i Sarhang-i Doktor Aghlipour beh Millat-i Irān: Mordād 1367" (Box 63)
      - Unlabeled, undated (Box 63)
  - 7-inch open reels, 1982-1983; undated
    - "No. 2,", undated (Box 64)
    - Iranian music programming, undated (Box 64)
    - "Saturday October 30, Subject: Laura-Grass Roots,", undated (Box 64)
    - "Dr. Ansari,", undated (Box 64)
    - "First Baptist Church,", 1982 October (Box 64)
    - "Insight week of...", 1983 April 24 (Box 64)
    - "Insight week of...,", 1983 June 19 (Box 64)
    - "Unlabeled,", undated (Box 64)
      12 reels
  - 10-inch open reels, 1981-1983; undated
    - "Iranian Hour,", undated (Box 65)
    - "Iranian Hour Program," 59+ minutes, undated (Box 65)
    - "Barnāmeh Shumārah-yi 2,", undated (Box 65)
    - "Iran Freedom Movement (I.F.M.) WLMD" 56 minutes, 1981 August 9 (Box 65)
    - "I.F.M." 58 minutes, 1981 October 4 (Box 65)
    - "I.F.M. WLMD," 42 minutes,", 1981 October 18 (Box 65)
    - "I.F.M. WLMD" 56 minutes, 1981 October 25 (Box 65)
    - "I.F.M. WLMD" 57 minutes, 1981 November 1 (Box 65)
    - "I.F.M. WLMD" 58 minutes, 1981 November 27 (Box 65)
    - "I.F.M. WLMD" 45 minutes, 1981 December 6 (Box 65)
    - "I.F.M. WLMD" 45 minutes, 1981 December 13 (Box 65)
    - "I.F.M. WLMD" 48 minutes, 1981 December 20 (Box 65)
    - "I.F.M. WLMD" 46 minutes, 1981 December 27 (Box 65)
    - "I.F.M. WLMD" 53 minutes, 1982 January 10 (Box 65)
    - "I.F.M." 52 minutes, 1982 January 17 (Box 65)
    - "I.F.M. Sunday Radio WLMD" 58 minutes, 1982 February 21 (Box 65)
    - "I.F.M. Sunday Radio WLMD" 60 minutes, 1982 February 28 (Box 65)
    - "I.F.M.", 1982 March 14 (Box 65)
    - "Tape 1,", 1982 May 9 (Box 65)
    - "Tape 2,", 1982 May 9 (Box 66)
    - "Iranian Hour Program," 50+ minutes, 1982 July 25 (Box 66)
    - "Unlabeled,", 1982 November 28 (Box 66)
    - "5/29/83,", 1983 May 29 (Box 66)
    - "Iranian Hour Sunday 26th,", 1983 June 25 (Box 66)
    - "I.F.M.," 58 minutes, 1983 November 22 (Box 66)
    - Unlabeled, undated (Box 66)
      9 reels
- Oversize materials, 1975-1990; undated
  - Newspapers, 1975-1990
    - Iran Free Press, vol. 4, no. 4, 1975 February-March (Box 67)
      Official publication of the Free Republic of Iran
    - Bethesda Almanac, vol. 2, no. 50, 1990 July 26 (Box 67)
      Includes article about the 10 year anniversary of assassination of A. A. Tabatabai
    - Montgomery Journal, 1985 June 27-28 (Box 67)
      Includes articles regarding Islamic Education Center
  - Islamic Unity of Afghanistan Mujahideen posters and calendars, 1984 (Box 67)
  - Anti-Khomeini bulletin published by the World Association of Iranian Monarchist Students, undated (Box 67)
  - Flyer for event on Iran at Bethesda-Chevy Chase High School, undated (Box 67)
  - Iran Freedom Foundation announcement welcoming American hostages home, draft and published copy, 1981 (Box 67)
  - Poster depicting a sketch of a man about to be executed, issued by the Arash Kamangir Organization, undated (Box 67)
  - Poster issued by the Constitutional Councils U.S. Chapter, undated (Box 67)
  - Poster depicting an executed man with the caption "Human Rights Under Tyranny of Ruhollah Khomeini,", 1980s (Box 67)